

# **HOANG PHAN**

# **Business Analyst**

**Phone:** (+84) 32 6562 797

Email: <a href="mailto:hoangpm.qn96@gmail">hoangpm.qn96@gmail</a>

Birthday: Feb 16, 1996

**Address:** District 9, Ho Chi Minh City

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Business Analyst with 1 year of experience analyzing, solves problems, and give solutions for foreign clients across travel, news, booking, and trade center management fields.

My main responsibility is to receive basic requests from customers, then discussing with them and my teams, analyzing, researching and give the proposals suitable for them through UML diagrams, Business Process Modeling, example, and the document.

## **SKILL**

<b>Business Analysis</b>	BPMN, UML, Business Process Flow, Use case, UAT, Management Requirement Gathering, Build test plan and test report, Design wireframe, UI/UX Analyst, Brainstorming, Training
Project Management	Design Scope of Work
Methodologies	Agile, Waterfall
Software	Draw.io, Balsamiq, Adobe XD, MS Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint), Photoshop, Jira, Trello, Asana
Professional	Decision Making, Effective communication, Self-motivation, Team player
LANGUAGE	
English	High Intermediate
Vietnam	Native

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

## **Title: Business Analyst and Quality Control**

# **Company: Kyanon Digital**

I worked with Agile software development in all projects at Kyanon Digital.

#### 1. OurBetterWorld

(ourbetterworld.org and travel.ourbetterworld.org)

Our Better World is the digital storytelling initiative of the Singapore International Foundation.

- I gathered business and system requirements from the client; assisted and consulted the client in defining output requirements, formats, scopes of work and suggesting ideas.
- Research and give for the customer the wireframes and ideas of UI/UX.
- Write "Agile user stories"; acceptance criteria; constructing workflow charts and diagrams; writing specifications.
- Estimate workload with internal team, work with PM and PO to define which sections will do first, the priorities of each task to deliver on time.
- Work with the Project team (Developers, QA/QC) to review and transfer requirements through the development life cycle.
- Perform UAT to ensure that validated deliverables meet functional and design specifications and requirements.
- Create User guide and Release note when the sprint ended.

## 2. Crescent Mall Loyalty Application

(Crescent Mall App on Google Play and App store)

- Have the meeting with customers to discuss and kick off the project.
- Write the test plan, test cases and verify for both App and CMS of Crescent Mall Loyalty Application.
- Use SQL to verify data reports in CMS easier.
- Review and update the function specs of Crescent Mall management from colleagues.
- Write the report for testing to send to the customer every week.

Aug 2017 - May 2018

## **Title: Quality Control**

# Company: IMT solutions, Vietnam

I worked with Agile software development in all projects at IMT solutions.

## 1. Juscollege (juscollege.com)

Juscollege is a website which sells the tours for the students of Colleges in the USA, Canada, and Mexico.

- I created test cases and document for this website.
- Performing manual and automation testing to verify this website.
- Using the Jira tool to manage tasks; excel and google sheet to manage test cases.
- Query database to verify a few functions related to calculation and record.

## 2. Viettel booking, Veritas App, Jpay App.

(A private project, veritasbespoke.com, jpay.com)

- Reading the documents, workflow, design, and creating the test plan, test cases.
- Helping apps/websites more perfect, meet customer requirement.

#### Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

## Work as a Developer Freelancer with WordPress

Develop and custom a responsive blog with WordPress.

- I met and recommended new features which my customer needed to improve for his website.
- I created the tutorial videos which helped my customer easily to use his website.
- I suggested to him using Trello and we managed tasks on it. (https://trello.com/b/wGEsWLRC/worldsforus)
- Languages used: PHP, HTML, CSS.

## **EDUCATION**

2014 - 2019	Ho Chi Minh City University of Information Technology Software Engineering
Aug 2019 - Nov 2019	Colegio San Agustin - Language Skills Learning Center, Philippines. English as Second Language

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Student with 5 good merits of Vietnamese Student's Association of UIT (2015).
- Certificates of commendation of Ho Chi Minh Communist Youth Union and Ho Chi Minh Vietnam National Union of Student about volunteer work-section.
- Certificate about my level in English is High Intermediate at LSLC, Philippines.

## VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Former leader of the 6th and 7th Social Work Team UIT (SWT).
- Former member of the Secretariat and responsible for volunteering at the Vietnamese Students' Association of the University of Information Technology.
- Team leader of events at UIT: Love Winter (2015, 2016), Spring volunteer campaign 2016, Green summer volunteer campaign 2016, UIT leader 2017, and a lot of other volunteer events and workshops at SWT.